westjetvacations.com 2007-12-13

# Help: Privacy policy | WestJet Vacations

## Privacy Policy

At WestJet Vacations, we are committed to respecting your privacy. This policy describes how we collect, use and disclose your personal information.

#### What is personal information?

Personal information is information about an identifiable individual. Your personal information includes your name, address, telephone number(s), date of birth, e-mail address and any other information that identifies who you are or would allow someone to contact you.

#### What personal information of mine will WestJet Vacations   
collect and how will it be used?

When you browse our website, we do not collect personal information about you. Personal information only becomes known to WestJet Vacations when you provide it to us or when a third party, such as a travel agent, family member, credit card services provider or other party obtaining vacation services for you on your behalf, provides personal information to us with your consent.

If you book a vacation package with us, join our mailing list, participate in a program or enter a contest that may be offered by WestJet Vacations from time to time, you will be asked for personal information. Personal information may be collected by us through our call centre, our website, from you in person, or about you from a third party obtaining vacation services for you on your behalf with your consent.

It is our policy to collect personal information about you directly from you where possible, except where personal information about you will be collected from a third party obtaining vacation services for you on your behalf with your consent.

When you book a vacation package with us, or when someone else does on your behalf, we will ask for your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, date of birth, age(s) of travelling child(ren), if applicable, and credit card information. This information will be used for one or more of the following purposes:

  * to process your request for vacation services;
  * to process refunds; and
  * to contact you about your vacation package booking or about anything that may affect your vacation package booking.

If you decide to join our mailing list and be informed of seat sales and other promotional offers, we will ask for your name, address and e-mail address. We will also ask you whether you provide your consent to us to provide you with information on special offers from our partners. We will use your personal information to communicate such seat sales and promotional offers with you via e-mail. Other mailings, such as special partner offers, may be provided to you by WestJet Vacations on a similar basis. You may withdraw this consent at any time.

If you decide to participate in research surveys, you consent to WestJet Vacations providing your e-mail address or telephone number, or both, as selected by you, to a third party research firm to conduct market research studies on behalf of WestJet Vacations. This information will be used to compile survey responses on an aggregate basis for WestJet Vacation's internal market research studies.  You may withdraw this consent at any time.

WestJet Vacations may, with your consent, collect profile information about you (i.e. hotel and car preferences, etc.), as well as demographic information (i.e. education level, etc.).  This information will be used to communicate specific information to you based on the profile and demographic information you provide or to contact you about your travel patterns and your experiences when flying with us.  You may withdraw this consent at any time.

If you decide to enter a WestJet Vacations promotional contest, we will ask for your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, date of birth and any other information related to the promotion or contest that may be required by law. This information will be used to verify that you are of sufficient age to participate in any contest or to communicate with you in the event you are a contest winner.

In order to properly serve guests with special needs, WestJet Vacations may require additional personal information of such guests, including relevant medical information, special accommodation requests and information on particular requirements, such as whether a wheelchair, oxygen supply or other special equipment are required, information on connecting flights or connections, as well as additional contact information in the event of an emergency. 

We use "cookies" to store non-personal information and to track your traffic patterns on our website. The information is collected in an anonymous and aggregate form to compile general statistical data. Cookies do not give us access to any of your personal information.

WestJet Vacations uses third-party advertising technology to serve ads when you visit our website and certain sites on which we advertise, using information from your visits to our website and those other sites to serve more targeted ads to you. In the course of serving ads to you, a unique third-party cookie may be placed or recognized by your browser. In addition, we use pixels or transparent GIF files, often referred to as "web beacons", to help manage and optimize our online advertising. These are provided by DoubleClick, and enable our ad servers to recognize a browser's cookie when a browser visits our website and to learn which banner ads bring users to our website. The technology may also allow other service providers to receive information from our website related to our online advertising. With both cookies and web beacons, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable and does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address.

DoubleClick is subject to contractual restrictions with respect to personal information to protect your privacy. For more information about DoubleClick, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to

#### How will WestJet Vacations protect my personal   
information?

WestJet Vacations has sophisticated security measures and procedures in place to ensure that your personal information is protected from misuse and from unauthorized access.

However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit to us over the Internet.

#### How long will WestJet Vacations retain my personal   
information?

Personal information collected by WestJet Vacations is retained for as long as it is reasonably required for the purposes for which it was collected, or until you withdraw your consent to our retaining your personal information, or as permitted or required by law, following which it is securely destroyed or made anonymous. If you withdraw your consent to our retaining your personal information, we will advise you as to the consequences, if any, of your doing so.

#### Will WestJet Vacations disclose my personal information   
to third parties?

WestJet Vacations will disclose your personal information with your consent to third parties as required to process your request for vacation services, including flights, hotel and car bookings, or to provide other services to you, or as required by applicable law, or as otherwise set out in this policy. 

In the event that, following booking of a vacation package on your behalf by a travel agent, you, or a different travel agent contact us directly in order to make changes to your booking, the travel agent who made the initial booking will be advised of the changes. This is done in order to avoid you or the travel agent possibly becoming responsible for double bookings or unused flights or other services.

Travel agent access to online information from WestJet Vacations is governed both by WestJet Vacations policies and by restrictions and levels of permission set up by the travel agency. Personnel in each travel agent office may be able to gain access to personal information concerning all clients and customers of the travel agency. Access to your personal information may not be limited to the individual travel agent you have dealt with and any inquiries in relation to this should be directed to your travel agent.

In the event that, following booking of a vacation package on your behalf by a third party, you, or another party, contacts us directly in order to make changes to your booking, the third party who made your initial booking will be advised of the changes. This is done in order to avoid you or the third party possibly becoming responsible for double bookings or unused flights or other services.

Certain employers and other parties may be granted access to online information from WestJet Vacations with respect to your booking where your employer or other party made that booking on your behalf. Such access is governed by our TERMS OF USE. Such other party, including any others to whom it grants permission, will be able to gain access to personal information concerning all individuals for whom they have made bookings.

WestJet Vacations is continuously seeking ways in which to better serve you. WestJet may therefore also disclose personal information concerning you to other organizations that may have affiliated programs to WestJet Vacations or other offers of interest to you to allow them to contact you, but WestJet Vacations will do so only with your consent, which you may withdraw at any time.

WestJet Vacations may provide you with the opportunity to access products and services from third parties. Those third parties may collect, use and disclose personal information from you or about you in order to provide their products or services to you. The collection, use and disclosure of personal information by those third parties will be governed by their privacy policies and any consent you provide and, unless we advise you otherwise, WestJet Vacations has no access to or control over the personal information collected from you by those third parties.

Also, WestJet Vacations may be required by government authorities in either the U.S. or Canada or both to collect personal information, and that information may be disclosed to such authorities without your knowledge or consent as required by law. It is our policy to only collect and disclose what is required by law, and nothing further.

Otherwise, personal information provided by you or on your behalf to book flights or other vacation services will not be provided to any third party, including a spouse, family member, friend, coworker, or any other third party without your consent, or as required by law, or as otherwise provided in this privacy policy. 

To protect your privacy rights and personal information, and for security and legal purposes, we therefore cannot disclose your personal information to any individual contacting us and claiming either to be a spouse, family member, friend, coworker or otherwise entitled to your personal information, or claiming to have your consent for us to do so, unless and until we have verified with you that such individual does in fact have your consent.

#### How does WestJet Vacations obtain my consent to collect, use and disclose my personal information?

It is our policy to collect, use and disclose personal information about you with your knowledge and consent, unless otherwise required or allowed by law. Prior to collecting your personal information, it is our general policy to identify the purposes for doing so and to limit the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information to those purposes.

Generally, we will collect personal information from you, and use it and disclose it with express consent received from you or from someone on your behalf. There will be occasions where we will rely on opt-out consent with respect to contacting you with promotional offers that we feel will be of interest to you. We will use opt-out consent only in circumstances where the personal information in question is not sensitive, where the purposes and circumstances are limited and well-defined and brought to your attention at the time your personal information is collected, or where you are given an opportunity to opt out or withdraw your consent then or at any time by contacting us.

If we identify a new purpose for using or disclosing your personal information, unless otherwise required by law, we will contact you to obtain your consent for the new use or disclosure and we may use your contact information, including your e-mail address, to do so.

If a third party, including a family member or friend, or your employer or another party other than a travel agent, makes a booking on your behalf, that party will provide us with the same personal information that we would otherwise collect from you directly in order to book vacation services. Unless and until we are advised otherwise, we will consider such third party to have your authority to provide us with your personal information to be used and disclosed pursuant to this privacy policy. Collection, use and disclosure of your personal information by a third party will be subject to your dealings with them and any applicable privacy policy and practices they may have.

When you book with us through a travel agent, your travel agent will provide us with the same personal information that we would otherwise collect from you directly in order to book vacation services. Unless and until we are advised otherwise, we will consider a travel agent to have your authority to provide us with your personal information to be used and disclosed to us pursuant to this privacy policy. Collection, use and disclosure of your personal information by your travel agent will be subject to your dealings with the travel agent and their privacy policies and practices.

#### How do I access my personal information?

To verify the accuracy and completeness of any information in your file, to update any of your information, to see a copy of the information we have on file about you, or to see an account of the use that has been made of your information, simply contact us at:

**Privacy Manager, Customer Care**

**Calgary Calling Area:** (403) 444-2484

**Toll Free:** 1-877-WJ CARES (1-877-952-2737) 

**Fax:** (403) 444-2494

You may also use the above contact information to withdraw any consent you have provided. We may require that requests for access to personal information or withdrawals of consent be received by us by e-mail, fax, mail or otherwise in written form. We will also require that you provide sufficient information to allow us to locate your information to deal with your request.

#### What if I have questions or concerns?

You may direct any questions or concerns about this policy to us or register a concern or complaint with us by using the above contact information. It is our policy to respond to all inquiries, requests for access to personal information and concerns or complaints within 30 days of our receiving them unless otherwise allowed or required by law. If we cannot fully respond within 30 days, we will still advise you of that within 30 days.

However, we cannot give you access to personal information that we do not have, or that would disclose personal information concerning another individual without their consent, or that we otherwise cannot disclose under applicable law. Where possible to do so, we will sever out information we can provide from information we cannot, and provide with the information we are able to provide. We reserve the right, in limited circumstances, to refuse to provide access to information where not legally required to do so.  In any case where we refuse access to information, we will advise you of the reasons for doing so, the name of a person who can answer any questions you may have, and other details of your legal rights.

#### How will I be informed of changes to this privacy policy?

This policy may be modified from time to time by posting updated versions on the WestJet Vacations website.
